Michael John Iringan

425.299.9407 • Everett, WA 98203 • mjiringan@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-iringan/ • U.S. Citizen

MANUFACTURING ENGINEER

Manufacturing Plans and Processes | ERP Systems | Tooling Design

Detail oriented and self-motivated manufacturing engineer with over seven years of experience implementing, coordinating, and overseeing manufacturing processes. Able to work collaboratively with multi-disciplinary teams to optimize business operations and improve quality. Experienced in utilizing critical thinking to resolve issues in manufacturing, design, and the supply chain.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jamco America – Everett, WA

July 2014 - PRESENT

Lead Manufacturing Engineer – ERP Systems (March 2020 – Present)

Manufacturing Engineer (July 2014 – March 2020)

Responsible for planning, directing, and coordinating manufacturing processes and process plans.

Represents Manufacturing Engineering in cross functional teams, such as Design Build Team, ERP Board, and Material Review Board. Serves as ERP administrator and subject matter expert, in charge of part master settings, process plans, and configuration management.

- Translated engineering designs into process plans of unique assemblies used in Jamco's premium class seats, aircraft modification packages and flight deck door bulkheads to facilitate daily manufacturing operations.
- Helped establish the production layout and flow of Jamco's Venture line of premium aircraft seats products, building assemblies of varying complexity, enabling just-in-time production of business class seat products.
- Developed "design for manufacturability" rules and guidelines for design engineers reducing complex bills of material and increasing clarity and standardization in drawings.
- Co-developed a new part numbering system with a multidisciplinary team of design engineers, cost analysts, and operations managers - improving visibility of part commodity type, configuration, and standard formatting through part number syntax.
- Introduced documentation to incorporate serial number configuration control of numerous seat configurations, providing clear configuration visibility to aid in post-delivery customer support.
- Co-authored a part array matrix document with cost analysts to communicate and provide quick references to hundreds of similar panel assemblies, providing quick access to key manufacturing information.
- Created a manufacturing procedure for printing polycarbonate placards from graphic file formats to introduce reliable, scalable, and repeatable short run placard manufacturing, reducing placard costs by up to 90%.

Michael John Iringan 425.299.9407

• Engaged in 5S, Kaizen, and other lean manufacturing exercises with multi-disciplinary teams to increase efficiency and lower costs of mature seats and aircraft monument production lines.

- Collaborated with shop mechanics and fellow manufacturing engineers to design tooling and shop aids with CAD systems (CATIA and SolidWorks) to improve takt times and reduce scrap rates of various assemblies.
- Participated in company audits and collaborated with quality engineering, quality control, and various other departments to implement corrective and preventative actions against nonconforming manufacturing processes to comply with IS9100.
- Collaborated with software developers and the Jamco ERP board to develop a
 dashboard/notification addon within Epicor to inform downstream operations of upcoming
 design changes, allowing pre-emptive configuration control planning and reduced rework costs.
- Collaborated with software developers to test and introduce CADLink, a software program that converts PDM model data to ERP data, reducing ERP process planning and part master work scope by up to 75 percent.

EDUCATION

University of Washington – Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Science in Materials Science and Engineering – June 2014

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Microsoft Office programs: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio
- Task management programs: Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Project, Slack, ClickUp
- CAD: CATIA, Solidworks
- ERP Systems: Epicor 10, Epicor 9
- PLM/PDM: SmarTeam, EPDM
- Lean/Kaizen
- GD&T

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

- Society for the Advancement of Material and Process Engineering (2013 Present)
- The Minerals, Metals & Materials Society (2013 Present)